<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GameMaker on Maksym Postument</title><link>https://mpostument.com/tags/gamemaker/</link><description>Recent content in GameMaker on Maksym Postument</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 18:48:32 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mpostument.com/tags/gamemaker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Game Maker - Variables</title><link>https://mpostument.com/2022/10/30/variables/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 18:48:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mpostument.com/2022/10/30/variables/</guid><description>Hello!
Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the world of game development with Game Maker 2. And today we&amp;rsquo;ll start with options in Game Maker. Let&amp;rsquo;s create a new project by selecting ``New Blank&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; and naming its variables.
Object Parameters can be added to objects. The object can be almost anything, starting with the hero and enemies, and ending with objects that control some logic in the game. Right-click the Objects folder in the Assets Browser to create an object and select Create -&amp;gt; Object.</description><content>&lt;p>Hello!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the world of game development with Game Maker 2. And today we&amp;rsquo;ll start with options in Game Maker. Let&amp;rsquo;s create a new project by selecting ``New Blank&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; and naming its variables.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/new_project.png" alt="project">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="object">Object&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Parameters can be added to objects. The object can be almost anything, starting with the hero and enemies, and ending with objects that control some logic in the game. Right-click the Objects folder in the Assets Browser to create an object and select Create -&amp;gt; Object.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/object.jpg" alt="object_create">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An object named Object1 will be created. It needs to be renamed immediately. It is recommended to add a prefix to the name because if we have an object with the name hero and we want to add a sprite that will also be called hero, we will get an error that a file with that name already exists. Therefore, each object must have the obj_ prefix. Thus, the object that I will create will be called obj_vars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After creation, the object will open immediately. Here you can specify a sprite for the object, specify whether it will be visible, and a few more options. Now we are interested in the events window. This is where we will write the code that will control our object.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/static/game_maker/object_params.jpg" alt="Object_params">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click the Add Event button and select Create. Event type &lt;code>Create&lt;/code> is called when the object is created and it is convenient to set some initial characteristics here. Double-click the left mouse button to open the code editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/static/game_maker/create.jpg" alt="create">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="local-variables">Local Variables&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the editor, we will create &lt;code>heroExp&lt;/code> parameters, which will be responsible for the experience of our object. These parameters are of type integer. We will also add the parameter &lt;code>heroName&lt;/code>, which will be of type string, and the parameter &lt;code>heroAlive&lt;/code>, which will be of type bool&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>heroExp &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">50&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>heroName &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Maksym&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>heroAlive &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> true
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Now let&amp;rsquo;s add another type of event called a draw. It is responsible for displaying the object. To do this, click &lt;code>Add Event&lt;/code> again and select Draw -&amp;gt; Draw in the list. I will open the editor for this type of event and write the following in the code&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>draw_text(&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">20&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">20&lt;/span>, heroExp)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>draw_text(&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">20&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">40&lt;/span>, heroName)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>draw_text(&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">20&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">60&lt;/span>, heroAlive)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>The &lt;code>draw_text&lt;/code> function is used to display text, the first two parameters are the x and y coordinates, and the third parameter is the text to be displayed. Let&amp;rsquo;s now add our object to the room and try it and see what happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="add-the-object-to-a-room">Add the object to a room&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the &lt;code>Assets Browser&lt;/code> you need to open the &lt;code>Rooms&lt;/code> folder and double-click on &lt;code>Room1&lt;/code>. The room window will open. In the top left, &lt;code>Instances&lt;/code> must be selected to be able to add objects to the room. Now our object can be simply dragged into the room. It is also worth changing the background color so that the text displaying the object is visible. To do this, in the room options, you need to select ``Background&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; and choose a color (Color option). I chose black because the text will be white.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/room_params.jpg" alt="room_params">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that everything is ready, press F5 to start the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/static/game_maker/var_output.jpg" alt="var_print">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dynamically-change-variables-value">Dynamically change variables value&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now let&amp;rsquo;s try to add an event that will change the value of our parameters. Let&amp;rsquo;s add the &lt;code>Key Press - Up&lt;/code> event, which will be called every time the &lt;code>Up&lt;/code> button is pressed on the keyboard, and the &lt;code>Key Press - Space&lt;/code> event. The up button will add experience to our object and the space button will kill our object.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Add the following to the &lt;code>Key Press - Up&lt;/code> code&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>heroExp&lt;span style="color:#f92672">++&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>А в &lt;code>Key Press - Space&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>heroAlive &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> false
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>And let&amp;rsquo;s start the game. If you press &lt;code>Up&lt;/code> or &lt;code>Space&lt;/code>, the parameters will be changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="global-vars">Global Vars&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Local parameters are available only within one object. If you want to add a parameter to which all objects will have access, you need to add &lt;code>global.&lt;/code> before the name of the parameter. Example&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">global&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>heroAlive &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> true
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>And now this parameter can be changed or used in other objects&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="video">Video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Coming soon&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>