<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GameMaker on Maksym Postument</title><link>https://mpostument.com/categories/gamemaker/</link><description>Recent content in GameMaker on Maksym Postument</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 19:17:15 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mpostument.com/categories/gamemaker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Game Maker - Coordinates</title><link>https://mpostument.com/2022/11/04/coordinates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 19:17:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mpostument.com/2022/11/04/coordinates/</guid><description>Hello!
Let&amp;rsquo;s consider how coordinates work in Game Maker.
Room coordinates I will open the room (Room1) and if you move the mouse to the upper left corner, the coordinates x = 0, y = 0 will be there. If you move to the right/left, the x coordinate will change, and if you move up/down, the y coordinate will change.
This is the basic information you need to know by coordinates.</description><content>&lt;p>Hello!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s consider how coordinates work in Game Maker.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="room-coordinates">Room coordinates&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I will open the room (Room1) and if you move the mouse to the upper left corner, the coordinates x = 0, y = 0 will be there. If you move to the right/left, the x coordinate will change, and if you move up/down, the y coordinate will change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/room_coordinates.jpg" alt="room_coordinates">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the basic information you need to know by coordinates. Now let&amp;rsquo;s try to add an object and move it&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="object-coordinates">Object coordinates&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The object can be added to the room by any available coordinates. I will create an object. But for the object to be visible in the room, it needs a sprite. You can simply paint the object with some color. To do this, on the object page, you can click &lt;code>New Sprite&lt;/code> or Ctrl+Shift+N. A sprite window will open immediately where you can click &lt;code>Edit Image&lt;/code>, then a window will open in which you can draw your sprite&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/sprite_color.jpg" alt="sprite">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But a sprite will be created with the name Sprite1 and in the objects folder. It should be renamed and moved to the Sprites folder. I will rename it to &lt;code>spr_vars&lt;/code> so that it is clear that the sprite refers to my object called &lt;code>obj_vars&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now you can open the room and drag the object there&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/obj_in_room.jpg" alt="obj_in_room">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also modify the object so that it prints the coordinates in which it is located.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will add the event &lt;code>Create&lt;/code> to the object in which I will specify the initial coordinates&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>x &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">0&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>y &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">0&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>I will also add the &lt;code>Draw&lt;/code> event in which I will display the coordinates. I will use the &lt;code>draw_text&lt;/code> which is a method already known from previous posts. Before displaying the text, you need to add &lt;code>draw_self()&lt;/code> to draw the object itself. And then two execution of the &lt;code>draw_text&lt;/code> method for the X and Y coordinates. As the first argument, I pass x, which is equal to the x coordinate of the object. The same with y, but I shift the text by the y coordinate so that the text does not overlap with each other. And I print the following text &amp;ldquo;X: 0&amp;rdquo;. To do this, I add the string &amp;ldquo;X:&amp;rdquo; to the x coordinate. But since the x coordinate is an int, I first need to convert it to the string type.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>draw_self()
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>draw_text(x, y&lt;span style="color:#f92672">+&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">5&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;X:&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">+&lt;/span> string(x))
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>draw_text(x, y&lt;span style="color:#f92672">+&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">20&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Y:&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">+&lt;/span> string(y))
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Press F5 to start the game&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/obj_with_coords.jpg" alt="obj_with_coords">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now let&amp;rsquo;s add the ability to move the object and see the coordinates of the object. I&amp;rsquo;ll do it with the &lt;code>Global Left Down&lt;/code> type event. why do you need global? To be able to click anywhere in the room. If you use &lt;code>Left Down&lt;/code>, the click will be counted only if it is made on the object. And I will add the following code&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>x &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> mouse_x
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>y &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> mouse_y
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>This code changes the coordinates of the object to the coordinates of the mouse cursor&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/move_coordinates.jpg" alt="move_coordinates">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="origin">Origin&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Every time we click, the upper left corner of the object is placed at this point. This is because the origin is set there. Origin is specified at the sprite level and can be changed. To do this, you need to open the sprite and you will immediately see that the origin is set to the upper left corner. With the help of the mouse, you can move it to any point or choose one of the existing options such as Top Left, Top Center, and others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/origin.jpg" alt="origin">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I move the origin to another point and start the game and move the object, then exactly the place specified as the origin will fit in this point&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/center_origin.jpg" alt="center_origin">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But now, as you can see, the text that we display has shifted. Because it displays according to origin. Therefore, to redraw the text inside the object, the coordinates in the &lt;code>draw_text&lt;/code> method need to be changed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, this is the case if the origin is in the center&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>draw_self()
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>draw_text(x&lt;span style="color:#f92672">-&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">20&lt;/span>, y&lt;span style="color:#f92672">-&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">15&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;X:&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">+&lt;/span> string(x))
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>draw_text(x&lt;span style="color:#f92672">-&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">20&lt;/span>, y, &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Y:&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">+&lt;/span> string(y))
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;h2 id="video">Video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Coming soon&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Game Maker - Variables</title><link>https://mpostument.com/2022/10/30/variables/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 18:48:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://mpostument.com/2022/10/30/variables/</guid><description>Hello!
Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the world of game development with Game Maker 2. And today we&amp;rsquo;ll start with options in Game Maker. Let&amp;rsquo;s create a new project by selecting New Blank and naming its variables.
Object Parameters can be added to objects. The object can be almost anything, starting with the hero and enemies, and ending with objects that control some logic in the game. Right-click the Objects folder in the Assets Browser to create an object and select Create -&amp;gt; Object.</description><content>&lt;p>Hello!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the world of game development with Game Maker 2. And today we&amp;rsquo;ll start with options in Game Maker. Let&amp;rsquo;s create a new project by selecting &lt;code>New Blank&lt;/code> and naming its variables.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/new_project.png" alt="project">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="object">Object&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Parameters can be added to objects. The object can be almost anything, starting with the hero and enemies, and ending with objects that control some logic in the game. Right-click the Objects folder in the Assets Browser to create an object and select Create -&amp;gt; Object.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/object.jpg" alt="object_create">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An object named Object1 will be created. It needs to be renamed immediately. It is recommended to add a prefix to the name because if we have an object with the name hero and we want to add a sprite that will also be called hero, we will get an error that a file with that name already exists. Therefore, each object must have the obj_ prefix. Thus, the object that I will create will be called obj_vars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After creation, the object will open immediately. Here you can specify a sprite for the object, specify whether it will be visible, and a few more options. Now we are interested in the events window. This is where we will write the code that will control our object.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/object_params.jpg" alt="Object_params">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click the Add Event button and select Create. Event type &lt;code>Create&lt;/code> is called when the object is created and it is convenient to set some initial characteristics here. Double-click the left mouse button to open the code editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/create.jpg" alt="create">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="local-variables">Local Variables&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the editor, we will create &lt;code>heroExp&lt;/code> parameters, which will be responsible for the experience of our object. These parameters are of type integer. We will also add the parameter &lt;code>heroName&lt;/code>, which will be of type string, and the parameter &lt;code>heroAlive&lt;/code>, which will be of type bool&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>heroExp &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">50&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>heroName &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Maksym&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>heroAlive &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> true
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Now let&amp;rsquo;s add another type of event called a draw. It is responsible for displaying the object. To do this, click &lt;code>Add Event&lt;/code> again and select Draw -&amp;gt; Draw in the list. I will open the editor for this type of event and write the following in the code&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>draw_text(&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">20&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">20&lt;/span>, heroExp)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>draw_text(&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">20&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">40&lt;/span>, heroName)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>draw_text(&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">20&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">60&lt;/span>, heroAlive)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>The &lt;code>draw_text&lt;/code> function is used to display text, the first two parameters are the x and y coordinates, and the third parameter is the text to be displayed. Let&amp;rsquo;s now add our object to the room and try it and see what happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="add-the-object-to-a-room">Add the object to a room&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the &lt;code>Assets Browser&lt;/code> you need to open the &lt;code>Rooms&lt;/code> folder and double-click on &lt;code>Room1&lt;/code>. The room window will open. In the top left, &lt;code>Instances&lt;/code> must be selected to be able to add objects to the room. Now our object can be simply dragged into the room. It is also worth changing the background color so that the text displaying the object is visible. To do this, in the room options, you need to select ``Background&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; and choose a color (Color option). I chose black because the text will be white.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/room_params.jpg" alt="room_params">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that everything is ready, press F5 to start the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/game_maker/var_output.jpg" alt="var_print">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dynamically-change-variables-value">Dynamically change variables value&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now let&amp;rsquo;s try to add an event that will change the value of our parameters. Let&amp;rsquo;s add the &lt;code>Key Press - Up&lt;/code> event, which will be called every time the &lt;code>Up&lt;/code> button is pressed on the keyboard, and the &lt;code>Key Press - Space&lt;/code> event. The up button will add experience to our object and the space button will kill our object.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Add the following to the &lt;code>Key Press - Up&lt;/code> code&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>heroExp&lt;span style="color:#f92672">++&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>And next code to &lt;code>Key Press - Space&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>heroAlive &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> false
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>And let&amp;rsquo;s start the game. If you press &lt;code>Up&lt;/code> or &lt;code>Space&lt;/code>, the parameters will be changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="global-vars">Global Vars&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Local parameters are available only within one object. If you want to add a parameter to which all objects will have access, you need to add &lt;code>global.&lt;/code> before the name of the parameter. Example&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">global&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>heroAlive &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> true
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>And now this parameter can be changed or used in other objects&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="video">Video&lt;/h2>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0yEsno2nMbE" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></content></item></channel></rss>