<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mpostument.com</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on mpostument.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:19:52 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Custom Dns for Github Pages</title><link>/2020/11/02/custom-dns-for-github-pages-copy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:19:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>/2020/11/02/custom-dns-for-github-pages-copy/</guid><description>Hello!
Today I want to show how you can add custom DNS for the GithubPages site.
This requires a few steps. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with domain name registration. I chose Namecheap to register my domain name. Open Namecheap website and in the search you need to enter the name you want to buy. Once you found what you are looking for and add it to your card.
It says Taken next to my domain name because I already bought it.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Hugo With Github Actions and Pages</title><link>/2020/10/21/deploy-hugo-with-github-actions-and-pages/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 20:19:26 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/21/deploy-hugo-with-github-actions-and-pages/</guid><description>Hello!
I want to show how you can deploy a hugo website in GitHub Pages using github actions. That&amp;rsquo;s how I build my site.
Install Hugo Hugo can be downloaded from GitHub. Put the binary in the desired location.
GitHub setup In github you need to create two repositories, one is for .md files and the theme (content-mpostument in my case) and another will be used for GitHub Pages in which will be stored generated website with hugo (mpostument.</description></item><item><title>Blazor Server Authorization</title><link>/2020/10/17/blazor-server-authorization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 19:04:41 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/17/blazor-server-authorization/</guid><description>Hello!
Today we will look at how to add authorization to Blazor Server. To begin with we will create the new project in which authentication will be enabled.
There are several additional files in the authentication project that are responsible for authentication. A connection string will also be added to the database in the configuration file.
&amp;#34;ConnectionStrings&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;DefaultConnection&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Server=(localdb)\\mssqllocaldb;Database=aspnet-BlazorAuth-BD4B8646-B1A3-438C-8FFC-8C3A29438C24;Trusted_Connection=True;MultipleActiveResultSets=true&amp;#34; }, In the package management console, you need to run the Update-Database command to create the database and the required tables.</description></item><item><title>Blazor Forms</title><link>/2020/10/16/blazor-server-forms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 16:09:30 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/16/blazor-server-forms/</guid><description>Hello!
Let&amp;rsquo;s see how you can create a form in BlazorServer.
Start with the model. I will create a file Models/User.cs, which will contain fields for the form.
namespace BlazorLearn.Models { public class User { public string UserName { get; set; } public string LastName { get; set; } public string Email { get; set; } public int Age { get; set; } public string Gender { get; set; } } } For the model to be available in razor components, it must be added to _Imports.</description></item><item><title>Events in Blazor</title><link>/2020/10/15/events-in-blazor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 11:37:56 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/15/events-in-blazor/</guid><description>Hello!
Let&amp;rsquo;s see how you can transfer data from one component to another.
Button I will create a component called ThumbButton which will contain two buttons. Depending on which button is pressed, the corresponding method will be called and the data will be transferred to the parrent component. @Onclick specifies which method will be executed when the button is pressed.
To pass data to the parrent component, a property of type EventCallback&amp;lt;Thumb&amp;gt; is used, where Thumb is enum.</description></item><item><title>Component With Parameters</title><link>/2020/10/14/components-with-parameters/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 11:47:34 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/14/components-with-parameters/</guid><description>Hello!
Let&amp;rsquo;s see how you can use components in BlazorServer and pass parameters to them. To do this, make two classes Student and School which will be displayed on the page. These classes will be in the Models folder.
Model using System.Collections.Generic; namespace BlazorLearn.Models { public class School { public string Name { get; set; } public List&amp;lt;Student&amp;gt; Students { get; set; } } } namespace BlazorLearn.Models { public class Student { public string FirstName { get; set; } public string LastName { get; set; } } } Razor Component Now I will create razor components that will be responsible for displaying the data.</description></item><item><title>Three Ways to Organize Code in BlazorServer</title><link>/2020/10/13/three-ways-to-organize-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 13:42:30 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/13/three-ways-to-organize-code/</guid><description>Hello!
I want to show you how you can organize code in BlazorServer.
Code in client The first option is to store the code on the client (in a razor file). Take the Counter.razor file which combines html and c# code.
@page &amp;#34;/counter&amp;#34; &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Counter&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Current count: @currentCount&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;button class=&amp;#34;btn btn-primary&amp;#34; @onclick=&amp;#34;IncrementCount&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Click me&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt; @code { private int currentCount = 0; private void IncrementCount() { currentCount++; } } This page has a private currentCount variable and an IncrementCount method that increments this variable.</description></item><item><title>Create Page in Blazor</title><link>/2020/10/12/create-page-in-blazor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 11:57:31 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/12/create-page-in-blazor/</guid><description>Hello!
Today we will look at how you can create a new page in BlazorServer and add it to the menu.
Add new page To do this, right-click on the Pages folder and select Razor Component...
The following window will appear in which you need to enter the name and click Add.
The page will be created with the following content:
&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Test1&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt; @code { } To be able to open it in the browser at the beginning of the file you need to add @page&amp;quot; /test1&amp;quot; where test1 is the name of the endpoint.</description></item><item><title>Blazor Server Logging</title><link>/2020/10/10/blazor-server-logging/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:01:49 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/10/blazor-server-logging/</guid><description>Hi!
Today we will see how to configure logging in BlazorServer. Immediately after creating a project, the appsettings.json file will be in the root of the project.
{ &amp;#34;Logging&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;LogLevel&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;Default&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Information&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Microsoft&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Warning&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Microsoft.Hosting.Lifetime&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Information&amp;#34; } }, &amp;#34;AllowedHosts&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;*&amp;#34; } This is where logging settings are set. LogLevel starts with Default which have value Information. This means that the default log level will be Information. Next is Microsoft with the Warning level, respectively for namespace Microsoft the login level will be Warning.</description></item><item><title>Blazor Dependency Injection</title><link>/2020/10/07/blazor-server-dependency-injection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 21:15:25 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/07/blazor-server-dependency-injection/</guid><description>Hi!
Today we will talk about how dependency injection works in blazor server. If you are familiar with dependency injection in asp.net core then there are no differences.
Dependency injection is configured in Startup.cs at the root of the project. After creating the project, it will look like this
public void ConfigureServices(IServiceCollection services) { services.AddRazorPages(); services.AddServerSideBlazor(); services.AddSingleton&amp;lt;WeatherForecastService&amp;gt;(); } Let&amp;rsquo;s see what happens here. services.AddRazorPages() - adds razor pages support to the project services.</description></item><item><title>Blazor Server Error Handling</title><link>/2020/10/06/blazor-server-error-handling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 19:31:30 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/06/blazor-server-error-handling/</guid><description>Hello!
Today we will look at how you can change the error messages in Blazor Server. There are two types of errors page does not exist and exception. You can change the message that will be displayed in both cases. The first thing to consider is how to change the message displayed to the user in the case of exception.
Exception Error In the Pages/_Host.cshtml file, this section is responsible for displaying the error:</description></item><item><title>Blazor Server Routing</title><link>/2020/10/01/blazor-server-routing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 21:09:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/01/blazor-server-routing/</guid><description>Hello! Today I want to tell you how routing works in Blazor Server.
Routing starts in the Startup.cs file. The following code will responsible for it
app.UseRouting(); app.UseEndpoints(endpoints =&amp;gt; { endpoints.MapBlazorHub(); endpoints.MapFallbackToPage(&amp;#34;/_Host&amp;#34;); }); app.UseRouting(); came from asp.net and adds route matching to the middleware pipeline. This middleware looks at the set of endpoints defined in the app, and selects the best match based on the request.
app.UseEndpoints() adds endpoint execution to the middleware pipeline.</description></item><item><title>Nightfall Dlp Configuration</title><link>/2020/09/30/nightfall-dlp-configuration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 21:52:21 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/09/30/nightfall-dlp-configuration/</guid><description>Hi there!
I want to talk today about DLP Nightfall. The Nightfall DLP Action scans your code commits upon Pull Request for sensitive information - like credentials &amp;amp; secrets, PII, credit card numbers &amp;amp; more - and posts review comments to your code hosting service automatically. The Nightfall DLP Action is intended to be used as a part of your CI to simplify the development process, improve your security, and ensure you never accidentally leak secrets or other sensitive information via an accidental commit.</description></item><item><title>Deploy to ec2 with codedship</title><link>/2020/09/16/deploy-to-ec2-with-codeship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 20:24:40 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/09/16/deploy-to-ec2-with-codeship/</guid><description>Hi there!
Today I want to show how you can deploy code on AWS EC2 using CodeShip Basic. To do this, I will use the integration of Codeship with AWS CodeDeploy.
CodeShip Configuration First you need to add a repository to CodeShip and go to the Deploy page Add a branch from which code will be deployed to ec2. In my case, the branch is master. Once the branch is added you need to scroll down to the Deployment section.</description></item><item><title>Get Lambdas in Vpc With Go</title><link>/2020/09/01/get-lambdas-in-vpc-with-go/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 17:40:16 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/09/01/get-lambdas-in-vpc-with-go/</guid><description>Hi there!
Today I want to tell you how with go you can get a list of all AWS Lambda that are in the VPC. First you need to install golang. The latest version can be downloaded from the official website.
Once golang is installed, create a folder for the scripts mkdir awsscripts
Next you need to initialize the go.mod file. This file stores all the dependencies on external packages, and at the same time will make the go code module.</description></item><item><title>Build Dotnet Core With Travis</title><link>/2020/08/31/build-dotnet-core-with-travis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 13:24:40 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/08/31/build-dotnet-core-with-travis/</guid><description>Hello!
Today I want to show how you can build and deploy .net core with Travis.
To get started, you need to create a Travis account. This requires you to login with your GitHub account. .travis.yml Configuration The next step is to create a .travis.yml file in the root of the repository.
Example of my configuration file:
language: csharp mono: none dotnet: 3.1.4 solution: awstaghelper.sln install: - dotnet restore script: - dotnet build --configuration Release --runtime win-x64 --output win-x64 - dotnet build --configuration Release --runtime win-x86 --output win-x86 - dotnet build --configuration Release --runtime linux-x64 --output linux-x64 - dotnet build --configuration Release --runtime osx-x64 --output osx-x64 before_deploy: - zip -r9 win-x64.</description></item><item><title>awstaghelper</title><link>/projects/awstaghelper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/awstaghelper/</guid><description>About project Tags are critical to managing AWS resources at scale. Awstaghelper provides a command line tool to ease adding and managing tags to and from CSV files across the wide range of AWS resources.
Install Download the latest binary from releases
Docs https://github.com/mpostument/awstaghelper</description></item><item><title>Wishlist2Text</title><link>/projects/wishlist2text/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/wishlist2text/</guid><description>About project Scrappe your steam wishlist in text format and it later for trading
Install Go to wishlist2text Enter your name and press button</description></item></channel></rss>