<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>mpostument.com</title>
    <link>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/</link>
    <description>Recent content on mpostument.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 21:59:31 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Artistic Journey Unveiled: Exploring the Fundamentals of Drawing and Perspective</title>
      <link>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/nma/fundamentals_of_drawing_and_perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 21:59:31 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/nma/fundamentals_of_drawing_and_perspective/</guid>
      <description>Join us as we delve into the mesmerizing world of drawing and perspective in the &amp;#39;Fundamentals of Drawing and Perspective&amp;#39; course. Discover the art of sketching geometric forms, mastering light and shadow, and unveiling the secrets of perspective. Embrace the challenges, growth, and artistic expression that unfold throughout this creative odyssey. Let your passion for art soar and embark on a remarkable adventure of self-discovery and artistic exploration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Art of Observation: Journey through the &#39;Fundamentals of Observational Drawing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/nma/fundamentals_observational_drawing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 20:10:31 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/nma/fundamentals_observational_drawing/</guid>
      <description>Join me on an artistic journey as I delve into the captivating world of observational drawing through the &amp;#39;Fundamentals of Observational Drawing&amp;#39; course at New Master Academy. Discover the challenges, insights, and progress made as I explore fundamental techniques, deepen my understanding of light and shadow, tackle still life compositions, and even venture into the intricacies of drawing the human head. This transformative experience not only reinforces the foundations but also opens up new avenues for artistic expression. Don&amp;#39;t miss out on this captivating exploration of observation in art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey into Artistry: Exploring New Master Academy&#39;s Drawing Foundations</title>
      <link>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/nma/drawing_foundations_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 20:24:07 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/nma/drawing_foundations_1/</guid>
      <description>Embark on an artistic adventure as I delve into the transformative course &amp;#39;Drawing Foundations 1&amp;#39; by New Master Academy. From mastering basic drawing tools to conquering perspective and textures, join me as I share my progress and showcase the captivating artworks created along the way. Get ready to be inspired and discover the power of foundational drawing skills that will elevate your artistic journey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
