<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Drawing on Maksym Postument</title><link>https://mpostument.com/tags/drawing/</link><description>Recent content in Drawing on Maksym Postument</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 18:03:31 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mpostument.com/tags/drawing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Week Four: Landmarks</title><link>https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_four_landmark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 18:03:31 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_four_landmark/</guid><description>I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s already the end of week three, and now I&amp;rsquo;m eagerly stepping into the realm of week four! As I sat down to watch the theory video for this upcoming week, a sense of excitement mixed with a touch of trepidation washed over me. It became apparent that the challenges awaiting me in the days ahead are going to push my artistic skills to the limit.
One particular topic caught my attention—landmarks.</description><content>&lt;p>I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s already the end of week three, and now I&amp;rsquo;m eagerly stepping into the realm of week four! As I sat down to watch the theory video for this upcoming week, a sense of excitement mixed with a touch of trepidation washed over me. It became apparent that the challenges awaiting me in the days ahead are going to push my artistic skills to the limit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One particular topic caught my attention—landmarks. These elusive elements of drawing have always perplexed me. How does one accurately depict and perceive them? It&amp;rsquo;s like entering uncharted territory, a realm where my artistic compass feels slightly askew. But I&amp;rsquo;m determined not to let that deter me!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my quest for improvement, I&amp;rsquo;ve embarked on a journey with Proko, relying on his informative and illustrative example videos. They serve as my guiding light, illuminating the path towards understanding and mastering the art of drawing landmarks. By following along with Proko&amp;rsquo;s demonstrations, I hope to internalize the techniques and concepts, gradually building my confidence and honing my artistic intuition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes, it takes a combination of theory and practical application to truly grasp a concept. Armed with newfound knowledge, I&amp;rsquo;m ready to immerse myself in the world of drawing, armed with pencils and sketchbooks as my trusted companions. With each stroke and line, I strive to unlock the secrets of landmarks and gain a deeper understanding of their significance in creating realistic and captivating artwork.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, as I embark on this exciting and challenging week, I&amp;rsquo;m filled with a mix of determination, curiosity, and a hint of artistic vulnerability. But with Proko as my mentor and the joy of exploration fueling my creativity, I&amp;rsquo;m confident that I&amp;rsquo;ll make significant strides in my artistic journey. Here&amp;rsquo;s to pushing boundaries, overcoming obstacles, and discovering the artist within!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_four/1.jpg" alt="One">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_four/2.jpg" alt="Two">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_four/3.jpg" alt="Three">&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Week Three: Structure</title><link>https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_three_structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 11:29:47 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_three_structure/</guid><description>Week Two Completed: A Journey of Discovery and Progress!
Wow, the second week of my drawing adventure flew by, and I must say, it was an exhilarating experience! Surprisingly, I found it even easier than the first week, which boosted my confidence and fueled my artistic passion.
Now, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the exciting details of the upcoming third week. This week serves as a crucial stepping stone, paving the way for the remarkable progress yet to come.</description><content>&lt;p>Week Two Completed: A Journey of Discovery and Progress!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wow, the second week of my drawing adventure flew by, and I must say, it was an exhilarating experience! Surprisingly, I found it even easier than the first week, which boosted my confidence and fueled my artistic passion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the exciting details of the upcoming third week. This week serves as a crucial stepping stone, paving the way for the remarkable progress yet to come. Our task? Drawing boxes and cylinders. But don&amp;rsquo;t let their simplicity deceive you - they hold the key to unlocking a whole new level of artistic prowess!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We begin by observing real objects and translating their three-dimensional essence onto paper. It&amp;rsquo;s incredible how these basic geometric forms can capture the essence of everyday items, transforming them into visually captivating creations. And the real fun begins when we let our imagination soar, allowing boxes and cylinders to take on a whole new life of their own!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But that&amp;rsquo;s not all - brace yourself for the grand finale of the week: our furry, feathery, or scaly friends will grace our artistic journey. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s time to capture the charm of animals using the power of boxes, cylinders, and spheres. By simplifying their forms, we unlock the secrets to portraying their unique characters and capturing their essence with a fresh and dynamic perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As always, my blog will be a living canvas, continuously evolving throughout the week. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to share my progress and unveil my creations with all of you. Join me on this exhilarating artistic expedition, and let&amp;rsquo;s embark on a thrilling adventure together!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stay tuned for regular updates and captivating artwork that will surely inspire and ignite your own creative flame. Together, we&amp;rsquo;ll unleash the true power of imagination and transform ordinary lines into extraordinary masterpieces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keep those creative juices flowing, my friends!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_three/1.jpg" alt="One">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_three/2.jpg" alt="Two">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_three/3.jpg" alt="Three">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_three/4.jpg" alt="Four">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_three/5.jpg" alt="Five">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_three/6.jpg" alt="Six">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_three/7.jpg" alt="Seven">&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Week Two: Bean</title><link>https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two_bean/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 18:33:02 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two_bean/</guid><description>Join me as I unveil my artistic discoveries from the second week of Proko&amp;rsquo;s Figure Drawing Fundamentals course. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my progress and showcase how I learned to harness the power of the bean—a foundational element in capturing the human figure.
During this week, I delved into the fascinating concept of the &amp;ldquo;bean.&amp;rdquo; Acting as a simplified representation of the human form, it helped me capture gestures and movements with precision.</description><content>&lt;p>Join me as I unveil my artistic discoveries from the second week of Proko&amp;rsquo;s Figure Drawing Fundamentals course. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my progress and showcase how I learned to harness the power of the bean—a foundational element in capturing the human figure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this week, I delved into the fascinating concept of the &amp;ldquo;bean.&amp;rdquo; Acting as a simplified representation of the human form, it helped me capture gestures and movements with precision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take a glimpse at some of my finest drawings, where the bean played a pivotal role in capturing the dynamic beauty of the human figure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Post will be updated with more drawing during this week&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two/1.jpg" alt="One">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two/2.jpg" alt="Two">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two/3.jpg" alt="Three">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two/4.jpg" alt="Four">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two/5.jpg" alt="Five">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two/6.jpg" alt="Six">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two/7.jpg" alt="Seven">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two/8.jpg" alt="Eight">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two/9.jpg" alt="Nine">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two/10.jpg" alt="Ten">&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Week One: Gesture</title><link>https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_one_gesture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 21:33:02 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_one_gesture/</guid><description>Wow, what an eventful week it has been diving into the world of drawing! Following a well-thought-out plan I discovered on Reddit, specifically this invaluable post https://www.reddit.com/r/learnart/comments/dapk62/from_the_guy_who_made_the_most_comprehensive_list/, I embarked on my artistic journey.
The first topic that caught my attention was Figure Drawing by Proko. Throughout the week, I immersed myself in the captivating first lesson on Gesture, dedicating time each day to practice. The lesson itself was a treasure trove, featuring a variety of videos.</description><content>&lt;p>Wow, what an eventful week it has been diving into the world of drawing! Following a well-thought-out plan I discovered on Reddit, specifically this invaluable post &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/learnart/comments/dapk62/from_the_guy_who_made_the_most_comprehensive_list/">https://www.reddit.com/r/learnart/comments/dapk62/from_the_guy_who_made_the_most_comprehensive_list/&lt;/a>, I embarked on my artistic journey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first topic that caught my attention was Figure Drawing by Proko. Throughout the week, I immersed myself in the captivating first lesson on Gesture, dedicating time each day to practice. The lesson itself was a treasure trove, featuring a variety of videos. One video offered insightful guidance on drawing techniques, while the next showcased the author&amp;rsquo;s skillful demonstrations, accompanied by detailed explanations. Additionally, there were captivating videos of the author&amp;rsquo;s drawings, ranging from quick 30-second sketches to more elaborate 2-minute masterpieces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can&amp;rsquo;t help but share a glimpse of my progress over this week. Although only a selection of my works is showcased here due to their sheer abundance, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that I still consider them somewhat mediocre. However, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to keep in mind that this is just the beginning of my journey, and I eagerly await the transformative growth that lies ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_one/1.jpg" alt="One">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_one/2.jpg" alt="Two">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_one/3.jpg" alt="Three">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_one/4.jpg" alt="Four">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_one/5.jpg" alt="Five">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_one/6.jpg" alt="Six">
&lt;img src="https://mpostument.com/drawing/figure_drawing/week_one/7.jpg" alt="Seven">&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>