<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Drawing on mpostument.com</title>
    <link>https://mpostument.com/categories/drawing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drawing on mpostument.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 18:50:48 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mpostument.com/categories/drawing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Drawing Journey: Week One - Unleashing Creativity and Mastering the Basics</title>
      <link>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/drawing_basics/week_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 18:50:48 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/drawing_basics/week_one/</guid>
      <description>Embark on an inspiring drawing journey as I delve into the world of art, exploring drawing basics, mastering grip techniques, and embracing creativity. Join me as I document my progress, share practical exercises, and celebrate the joy of self-expression through the power of lines and shapes. Discover the transformative power of art and unleash your creative potential</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week Four: Landmarks</title>
      <link>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/figure_drawing/week_four_landmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 18:03:31 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/figure_drawing/week_four_landmark/</guid>
      <description>In the fourth week&amp;#39;s lesson, we covered the topic of landmarks in the context of the &amp;#39;Figure Drawing Fundamentals&amp;#39; course by Proko. This course provides a comprehensive overview and instruction on the essential principles and techniques of figure drawing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week Three: Structure</title>
      <link>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/figure_drawing/week_three_structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 11:29:47 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/figure_drawing/week_three_structure/</guid>
      <description>In the third week of my artistic journey, I&amp;#39;m delving into the fascinating topic of structure in drawing. As part of my exploration, I&amp;#39;m following the &amp;#39;Figure Drawing Fundamentals&amp;#39; course by Proko. This course provides valuable insights and techniques for understanding the underlying structures that give life and form to our artistic creations. Happy learning and creating!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week Two: Bean</title>
      <link>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two_bean/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 18:33:02 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/figure_drawing/week_two_bean/</guid>
      <description>In my second week of artistic exploration, I&amp;#39;m diving into the world of drawing beans. To guide me on this exciting journey, I&amp;#39;ve enrolled in the &amp;#39;Figure Drawing Fundamentals&amp;#39; course by Proko. This course provides comprehensive lessons and resources for mastering the art of drawing beans with precision and skill. Get ready to enhance your drawing skills and unleash your creativity!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week One: Gesture</title>
      <link>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/figure_drawing/week_one_gesture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 21:33:02 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/figure_drawing/week_one_gesture/</guid>
      <description>Hey, I recently embarked on my journey to learn drawing. This week, I&amp;#39;m diving into the fascinating world of gesture drawing through the &amp;#39;Figure Drawing Fundamentals&amp;#39; course by Proko. This course provides a solid foundation in understanding and capturing the dynamic and expressive qualities of the human form. Happy drawing!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
