<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Go on mpostument.com</title><link>/tags/go/</link><description>Recent content in Go on mpostument.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 18:56:24 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Latest post in GitHub readme</title><link>/2021/03/06/latest_post_in_github_readme/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 18:56:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>/2021/03/06/latest_post_in_github_readme/</guid><description>Hello!
Today I will show how to automatically generate GitHub Readme with the latest blog posts using go. In GitHub you need to create a repository named as your GitHub profile. My GitHub profile is called mpostument, so I&amp;rsquo;ll create a repository with the same name.
I clone the repository and call go mod init in it, in order to initialize the go module which will generate readme. At the root of the repository you need to create main.</description></item><item><title>Ebs Auto Resize</title><link>/2021/02/06/ebs-auto-resize/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 18:14:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>/2021/02/06/ebs-auto-resize/</guid><description>Hi there!
Today we will make a script for automatic resizing of EBS volume using golang and AWS SDK version 2. To do this, I need to perform a few steps: get a list of volumes, filter those volumes in which the amount of free memory is less than the threshold, find the ebs id that corresponds to this volume. Resize by a specified percentage and increase the disk size on the file system.</description></item><item><title>Failed Asg Event Notification</title><link>/2021/01/03/failed-asg-event-notification/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 17:57:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>/2021/01/03/failed-asg-event-notification/</guid><description>Hello!
Today I want to show how with the help of AWS Lambda and Golang you can get messages in slack when Autoscaling could not create an Ec2 server. Deploy I automate using serverless.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the installation of node and serverless. I use nvm to manage node versions.
curl -o- https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nvm-sh/nvm/v0.37.2/install.sh | bash nvm install v14.15.3 npm install -g serverless I will create a folder and initialize the go module in it.</description></item><item><title>Import Grafana Dashboards With Go</title><link>/2020/12/23/import-grafana-dashboards-with-go/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 23:18:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>/2020/12/23/import-grafana-dashboards-with-go/</guid><description>Hello!
In the previous post I showed how you can export dashboards from Grafana. Now let&amp;rsquo;s see how they can be imported into Grafana.
As always at the beginning there will be imports and main function
package grafana import ( &amp;#34;context&amp;#34; &amp;#34;encoding/json&amp;#34; &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; &amp;#34;io/ioutil&amp;#34; &amp;#34;log&amp;#34; &amp;#34;os&amp;#34; &amp;#34;strings&amp;#34; &amp;#34;github.com/grafana-tools/sdk&amp;#34; ) func main() { } I will add some parameters:
var ( filesInDir []os.FileInfo rawBoard []byte err error grafanaURL string apiKey string directory string ) filesInDir will store all dashboards from the file system.</description></item><item><title>Export Grafana Dashboards With Go</title><link>/2020/12/19/export-grafana-dashboards-with-go/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 18:27:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>/2020/12/19/export-grafana-dashboards-with-go/</guid><description>Hello!
Let&amp;rsquo;s check how you can use go to export dashboards from Grafana. For interaction with Grafana I use sdk. Sdk can be installed using go get github.com/grafana-tools/sdk.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start writing code. At the beginning of the file will be the package, import and main function
package main import ( &amp;#34;context&amp;#34; &amp;#34;encoding/json&amp;#34; &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; &amp;#34;log&amp;#34; &amp;#34;os&amp;#34; &amp;#34;github.com/grafana-tools/sdk&amp;#34; ) func main() { } ) I will add some parameters:
var ( boardLinks []sdk.</description></item><item><title>Filter Ebs Snapshot By Date With Go</title><link>/2020/12/05/filter-ebs-snapshot-by-date-with-go/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 17:53:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>/2020/12/05/filter-ebs-snapshot-by-date-with-go/</guid><description>Hello!
Today I will show how you can filter ebs snapshots by date with golang.
To begin with I will create a folder and in it, I will initialize the go module
mkdir snapshotFilter cd snapshotFilter go mod init snapshotFilter You need to create main.go which will contain the code. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the main function and imports
package main import ( &amp;#34;flag&amp;#34; &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; &amp;#34;log&amp;#34; &amp;#34;sort&amp;#34; &amp;#34;time&amp;#34; &amp;#34;github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go/aws&amp;#34; &amp;#34;github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go/aws/session&amp;#34; &amp;#34;github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go/service/ec2&amp;#34; ) func main() { sess := session.</description></item><item><title>Get Lambdas in Vpc With Go</title><link>/2020/09/01/get-lambdas-in-vpc-with-go/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 17:40:16 +0300</pubDate><guid>/2020/09/01/get-lambdas-in-vpc-with-go/</guid><description>Hi there!
Today I want to tell you how with go you can get a list of all AWS Lambda that are in the VPC. First you need to install golang. The latest version can be downloaded from the official website.
Once golang is installed, create a folder for the scripts mkdir awsscripts
Next you need to initialize the go.mod file. This file stores all the dependencies on external packages, and at the same time will make the go code module.</description></item></channel></rss>