<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>artistic journey on mpostument.com</title>
    <link>https://mpostument.com/tags/artistic-journey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in artistic journey on mpostument.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 21:42:55 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mpostument.com/tags/artistic-journey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Master Academy: Drawing With Force</title>
      <link>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/nma/drawing_with_force/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 21:42:55 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/nma/drawing_with_force/</guid>
      <description>Join me on my artistic journey as I share the highlights and insights from completing Mike Mattesi&amp;#39;s Drawing with Force course at NMA. Discover how I honed my figure drawing skills, delved into the world of force lines, and prepared for the next chapter in my art education journey. Follow along for valuable lessons and updates on my creative progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Master Academy: Fundamentals of Observational Drawing</title>
      <link>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/nma/fundamentals_observational_drawing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 20:10:31 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mpostument.com/posts/drawing/nma/fundamentals_observational_drawing/</guid>
      <description>Join me on an artistic journey as I delve into the captivating world of observational drawing through the &amp;#39;Fundamentals of Observational Drawing&amp;#39; course at New Master Academy. Discover the challenges, insights, and progress made as I explore fundamental techniques, deepen my understanding of light and shadow, tackle still life compositions, and even venture into the intricacies of drawing the human head. This transformative experience not only reinforces the foundations but also opens up new avenues for artistic expression. Don&amp;#39;t miss out on this captivating exploration of observation in art.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
